Jordan Zimmerman

Cloud Engineer at Elastic

jordan@jordanzimmerman.com

Summary

Jordan Zimmerman has had a distinguished career as a distributed systems and cloud developer. Formerly on the Platform team at Netflix, he is currently President/CEO of Aisa Software Consulting. He created Apache Curator, the popular Apache ZooKeeper client as well as other open source projects. He has been published in the Software Developer's Journal, the Cloudera Blog, an Addison-Wesley book and many other publications. He and his wife live in Panama City, Panama.

Experience

Member at The Apache Software Foundation

April 2017 - Present

Lead for Apache Curator

Cloud Engineer at Elastic

January 2016 - Present

- * Member of the Cloud core team
- * Part of platform team writing and deploying Elastic's cloud offering
- * Java and Scala Services
- * Docker, Elasticsearch, ZooKeeper, sbt, Vagrant, AWS

Committer at The Apache Software Foundation

March 2013 - Present

Apache Curator lead. Apache Curator is a Java/JVM client library for Apache ZooKeeper, a distributed coordination service. It includes a highlevel API framework and utilities to make using Apache ZooKeeper much easier and more reliable. It also includes recipes for common use cases and extensions such as service discovery and a Java 8 asynchronous DSL.

Senior Software Engineer Contractor at Blue Jeans Network

September 2014 - December 2015 (1 year 4 months)

- * Platform team
- * Java/REST services
- * Integrating Netflix OSS libraries
- * ZooKeeper

Senior Software Engineer Contractor at Qubole

December 2013 - September 2014 (10 months)

Member of team building cloud based Hadoop/Hive framework

Senior Software Engineer Contractor at Riot Games

July 2013 - December 2013 (6 months)

- * Big data and distributed cloud computing for the world's biggest online game, League of Legends.
- * Java REST services
- * Integrating Netflix OSS libraries

Senior Platform Engineer at Netflix

April 2011 - July 2013 (2 years 4 months)

- * Helped build the foundation shared libraries and infrastructure components that enables Netflix development in the Cloud
- * Member Platform team
- * Java services and libraries
- * Initiated the Netflix OSS project by open sourcing Curator now Apache Curator as well as Exhibitor and Governator

Architect at Proofpoint

March 2010 - April 2011 (1 year 2 months)

Software Architect in the Cloud Services group. Implemented a sharded, cloud-based Lucene search service. Helped architect new SaaS platform.

Principal Software Architect at SHOP.COM

1997 - March 2010 (13 years 3 months)

Architect of AMOS – Altura Merchant Operating System, e-commerce platform used for a variety of websites. Helped transition Altura Software from vendor of developer tools to a dot-com.

Senior Software Engineer

1992 - 1997 (6 years)

Senior Engineer in charge of Windows to Macintosh project. Technical Account Manager/Senior Engineer for several Macintosh to Windows projects. System design and implementation of Windows to Macintosh porting library. System design and implementation of QuickHelp - the WinHelp compatible online help system for Macintosh. QuickHelp was used by Apple Computer for its Macintosh Programmers Toolbox Assistant.

Software Engineer at Symantec Corporation

1991 - 1992 (2 years)

Implemented major components of Q&A for the Macintosh, a flat-file database with integrated word processing. Lead Engineer of an eight person team. Draw Engine - sophisticated color "draw-type" graphics module. Design Module - user-customizable forms module. Memory Management. Instituted source code control system. Decision maker regarding technical issues. Responsible for developing engineering plan.

Software Engineer

1988 - 1990 (3 years)

Sole engineer on version 2.0 of Movie Magic Scheduling, the industry standard project management tool for the Motion Picture industry. Designed and implemented new functionality. Made the code ANSI C compliant. Ported code to MS/DOS from Macintosh. Added Desk Accessory and Control Panel features to the porting library. UNIX development experience. MS/DOS and Windows development experience. Wrote portable memory manager for Macintosh and Windows.

Education

Van Nuys High School 1979 - 1982 Fulton Jr. High 1978 - 1981

Jordan Zimmerman

Cloud Engineer at Elastic

jordan@jordanzimmerman.com



Contact Jordan on LinkedIn